Finding Aid for the Richard P. Wunder Research Files, 1945-1989 MS.02
The Frick Collection/Frick Art Reference Library Archives
- Series I: Gian Paolo Panini, 1948-1984, 11.0 Linear feet (23 boxes)
  - Subseries 1: Artwork, circa 1948-1960
    - Paintings
      - New York (N.Y.), Art Collector's Association (Box 5, Folder 14-15)
        14 Archway, Statue of Marcus Aurelius
        15 Basilica of Maxentius and Ruins
      - New York (N.Y.), Berry-Hill Galleries -Pool of Bethesda (Box 5, Folder 16)
      - New York (N.Y.), Alex de Canedo -Soldiers on a Rocky Landscape (Box 5, Folder 17)
      - New York (N.Y.), Walter P. Chrysler (Box 5, Folder 18-19)
        18 Festival in Piazza Farnese
        19 Interior of the Parthenon
      - New York (N.Y.), Clarkes -Death Leap of Marcus Curtius (Box 5, Folder 20)
      - New York (N.Y.), David M. Koetser Gallery -Colosseum Series (Box 5, Folder 21)
      - New York (N.Y.), Paul Drey (Box 5, Folder 22-23)
        22 Colosseum and other Monuments
        23 Portico of Octavius and Colosseum
      - New York (N.Y.), Ehrich-Newhouse Galleries (Box 5, Folder 24-26)
        24 Colosseum Series
        25 Pantheon, Statue and Monuments
        26 Sphinx, Portico, Figures Examining a Relief
      - New York (N.Y.), French and Co. (Box 5, Folder 27-29)
        27 Ruined Arcade, Pyramid, Water in Foreground
        28 Ruins, Figures at the Seaside
        29 Ruins, Figures Conversing Near Seaside
      - New York (N.Y.), Arturo Grassi -Ruins with Soldiers Examining a Sarcophagus (Box 5, Folder 30)
      - New York (N.Y.), Simon Guggenheim -Pyramid, Pile of Ruins, Figures Conversing (Box 5, Folder 31)
      - New York (N.Y.), Hammer Galleries -Maison Carree, Nimes with Roman Monuments (Box 5, Folder 32)
      - New York (N.Y.), Howard Young Galleries (Box 5, Folder 33-38)
        33 Arch of Janus Series
        34 Archway, Obelisk, Ruins
        35 Garden, Ruins, Fountain
        36 Ruins, Elder Addressing a Group
        37 Ruins, Figures Listening to an Elder
        38 Ruins, Vase, Figure Addressing Others
      - New York (N.Y.), Lytle Hull (Box 5, Folder 39-40)
        39 The Campidoglio
        40 Piazza S. Pietr
      - New York (N.Y.), Mrs. John J. Ide -Ruins with Belisarius Begging Alms (Box 5, Folder 41)
      - New York (N.Y.), John Barnes Foundation -Interior of the Parthenon (Box 5, Folder 42)
      - New York (N.Y.), Kende Galleries -The Colosseum (Box 5, Folder 43)
      - New York (N.Y.), Kress Collection -Mass of Ruins with Arch, Lion Statue (Box 5, Folder 44)
      - New York (N.Y.), M. Knoedler and Co. (Box 5, Folder 45-57)
        45 Arch of Constantine and other Monuments
        46 Circular Temple, Portico, Figure Gesticulating
        47 Colosseum and other Monuments
        48-49 Colosseum Series
        50 Horsetamers and other Monuments
        51 Landscapes with Ruin
        52 Landscape with Ruins and Figures
        53 Nativity of the Angels
        54 Pantheon, Temple of Fortuna Virilis
        55 Pantheon and Other Monuments
        56 Statue of a River God and Colosseum
        57 Temple Portico, Arch of Titus and Figures
      - New York (N.Y.), Marie Sterner Galleries (Box 5, Folder 58-59)
        58 Ruins, Terrace and Statue of M. Aurelius
        59 View of the Forum
      - New York (N.Y.), Merwin Gallery -Temple of Antoninus and Faustina etc. (Box 5, Folder 60)
      - New York (N.Y.), Metropolitan Museum Picture Gallery (Box 5, Folder 61-63)
        61 Ancient Rome
        62 Interior of St. Peters
        63 Modern Rome
      - New York (N.Y.), Frederick Mont -Group of Figures Conversing (Box 5, Folder 64)
      - New York (N.Y.), Historical Society (Box 6, Folder 1-3)
        1-2 Mass of Ruins
        3 Palace Terrace Near the Sea
      - New York (N.Y.), Newhouse Galleries (Box 6, Folder 4-5)
        4 Mass of Roman Monuments, Figure on Horseback
        5 Ruins, Women and Shepherd Conversing
      - New York (N.Y.), Joseph V. Noble -Ruins (Box 6, Folder 6)
      - New York (N.Y.), Parke-Bernet (Box 6, Folder 7-17)
        7 Archway with Statue of Marcus Aurelius
        8 Archway, Pantheon, Statue of M. Aurelius
        9 Column of Trajan, Colosseum, Arch of Constantine
        10 Interior of St. Peters
        11 Ionic Archway, Statue of M. Aurelius
        12 Pile of Ruins and Arch
        13 Ruined Archway with Figures
        14 Ruins and Vegetation
        15 Statue, Portico, Colonnade, Figures
        16 Steps, Exedra, Statue of M. Aurelius
        17 Vase, Relief and Temple of Saturn
      - New York (N.Y.), Rains -Pile of Ruins and Arch (Box 6, Folder 18)
      - New York (N.Y.), Rosenberg and Stiebel (Box 6, Folder 19-20)
        19 Cleansing of the Temple, Christ Hiding Himself
        20 Interior of the Pantheon
      - New York (N.Y.), Schaeffer Galleries -Pyramid, Arch of Janus, Ruins and Figures (Box 6, Folder 21)
      - New York (N.Y.), Scott and Foules -Portico, Archway, Statue of the Aged Satyr (Box 6, Folder 22)
      - New York (N.Y.), Sedelmeyer and Co. (Box 6, Folder 23-24)
        23 Piazza di Monte Cavallo
        24 Piazza S. Pietro
      - New York (N.Y.), Leopoldo di Segni -Circular Temple and Pyramid (Box 6, Folder 25)
      - New York (N.Y.), Victor Sparks -Interior of the Baths of Diocletian (Box 6, Folder 26)
      - New York (N.Y.), Julius H. Weitzner (Box 6, Folder 27-29)
        27 Boat Landing Before a Palace
        28 Ruined Archway, Figure Gesticulating
        29 Soldiers Fighting Before a Palace at Night
      - New York (N.Y.), Richard P. Wunder -Belvedere Hermes, Archway, Pyramid (Box 6, Folder 30)
      - Northampton (England), Smith College Museum of Art (Box 6, Folder 31-32)
        31 Death Leap of Marcus Curtius
        32 Mass of Ruins with a Statue
      - Ottowa (Canada), National Gallery of Canada -Composite View of the Forum (Box 6, Folder 33)
      - Oxford (England), Ashmolean Museum (Box 6, Folder 34-36)
        34 Ruins, Statue and Figures
        35 Ruined Vaulted Chamber, Statues and Colosseum
        36 Circular Temple, Bearded Man Preaching
      - Paris (France), Brunner Galleries (Box 6, Folder 37-40)
        37 Colosseum and Other Ruins
        38 Roman Ruins with Temple of Fortuna Virilis
        39 Vase, Relief and Fragments
        40 Vase, Temples and Aqueduct
      - Paris (France), Ernest May -Colosseum Series (Box 6, Folder 41)
      - Paris (France), Galerie Trotti (Box 6, Folder 42-43)
        42 Ruins with Obelisk in a Landscape
        43 Landscape with Ruins
      - Paris (France), Drouots -Festival in Piazza di Spagna (Box 6, Folder 44-45)
      - Paris (France), Louvre (Box 6, Folder 46-64)
        46 Arch of Janus, Statue of Marcus Aurelius, Circular Temple
        47 Banquet
        48 Cleansing of the Temple
        49 Concert
        50 Concert in a Theater
        51 Corinthian Portico, Pantheon etc.
        52 Feast
        53 Festival in Piazza Navona
        54 Interior of St. Peters
        55 Ionic Archway in Which a Figure Addresses a Group
        56 Ionic Archway, Pyramid, Soldiers Opening a Tomb
        57 Picture Gallery Ancient Rome
        58 Picture Gallery Modern Rome
        59 Pool of Bethesda
        60 Pyramid, Portico, Statue of Flora
        61 Ruined Circular Arcade, Tiempetto in Rear
        62 Ruins with Shepherd and Woman Conversing
        63 Temples of Castor and Pollux and Mater Matuta, Female Addresses a Group
        64 Vase, Pyramid and Figures
      - Paris (France), François Heim (Box 6, Folder 65-67)
        65 Pyramid, Arch, Statue
        66 Vase in a Landscape
        67 Vase and Portico, Figures Examining a Relief
      - Paris (France), Prince Poniatowsky (Box 6, Folder 68-69)
        68 Luncheon Party in the Compagna
        69 Scene in the Roman Compagna
      - Philadelphia (Penn.), D. H. Carstairs -Ruins with Figure Preaching (Box 7, Folder 1-2)
      - Philadelphia (Penn.), Daniel H. Farr -Ruined Arcade with Group of Figures (Box 7, Folder 3)
      - Philadelphia (Penn.), Museum of Art (Box 7, Folder 4-6)
        4 Temple of Fortuna, Ruins of Arch
        5 Temple of Fortuna Virilis
        6 Temple of Neptune, Pantheon
      - Philadelphia (Penn.), Pasquale Farina (Box 7, Folder 7-8)
        7 Pyramid and Ruined Arch
        8 Ruined Arch with Shepherds
      - Philadelphia (Penn.), E. P. Richardson -Night Scene (Box 7, Folder 9)
      - Piacenza (Italy), Collegio Alberoni -Cleansing of the Temple (Box 7, Folder 10)
      - Piacenza (Italy), Museo Civico (Box 7, Folder 11-12)
        11 Ruins, Figures at a Fountain
        12 Vase, Pyramid and Figures
      - Piacenza (Italy), Nasalli-Rocca collection -Ruined Archway and Statue (Box 7, Folder 13)
      - Pittsburgh (Penn.), Mrs. C. H. Lehman (Box 7, Folder 14-16)
        14 Landscape with Colosseum
        15 Landscape with Roman Monuments
        16 Temple of Antoninus and Faustina
      - Potsdam (Germany), Schloss Sanssouci -View of Rome from the Vatican Gardens (Box 7, Folder 17)
      - Preston (England), F. Treasure -Ruins with Bacchanalian Subjects (Box 7, Folder 18)
      - Princeton (N.J.), University Art Museum -Ruins (Box 7, Folder 19)
      - Providence (R.I.), Rhode Island School of Design -Colosseum Series (Box 7, Folder 20)
      - Richmond (Va.), E. Croft-Murray -The Pool of Bethesda (Box 7, Folder 21)
      - Richmond (Va.), Virginia Museum of Art -Colosseum Series (Box 7, Folder 22)
      - Rome (Italy), Academia di S. Luca (Box 7, Folder 23-24)
        23 Alexander at the Tomb of Achilles
        24 Ruins with Relief, Figure Preaching
      - Rome (Italy), Antoninas -Corinthian Portico and Statue of a Roman (Box 7, Folder 25)
      - Rome (Italy), Michele de Benedetti -Arch of Janus, Column of Trajan, Pyramid (Box 7, Folder 26)
      - Rome (Italy), Galleria Corsini (Box 7, Folder 27-32)
        27 Baths of Diocletian, Horses in Foreground
        28 Four Door Panels
        29 Ruined Roman Bath with Figures
        30 Ruins, Woman and Shepherd Conversing
        31 Statue of a River God, Seated Figure
        32 View of the Forum
      - Rome (Italy), Galleria Nazionale -Arch with Marcus Aurelius Statue (Box 7, Folder 33)
      - Rome (Italy), Galleria Sangiorgi (Box 7, Folder 34-35)
        34 Historical Subject
        35 Wedding at Cana
      - Rome (Italy), Lunati Collection -Pantheon and Ruined Arcade (Box 7, Folder 36)
      - Rome (Italy), Montefiore collection (Box 7, Folder 37-38)
        37 Alexander at the Tomb of Achilles
        38 Ruins and Bearded Preacher
      - Rome (Italy), Museo di Roma -Exedra with M. Aurelius Statue (Box 7, Folder 39)
      - Rome (Italy), Palazzo Alberoni -Decoration of Salon (Box 7, Folder 40)
      - Rome (Italy), Palazzo de Carolis -Decorations (Box 7, Folder 41)
      - Rome (Italy), Palazzo Patrizi -Decorations (Box 7, Folder 42)
      - Rome (Italy), Palazzo de Quirinale (Box 7, Folder 43-45)
        43 Decorations, Mezzanini
        44 View of Piazza S. Maria Maggiore
        45 View of Palazzo Consulta
      - Rome (Italy), Palazzo Rospigliosi -Ruins and Figures by the Seaside (Box 7, Folder 46)
      - Rome (Italy), private collections (Box 7, Folder 47-50)
        47 Interior of the Colosseum
        48 Pantheon in Ruins, a Vase
        49 Relief, Urn, Ruins in a Landscape
        50 Ruined, Vaulted Chamber with Statue of M. Aurelius
      - Rome (Italy), S. Croce in Gerusalemme -Glorification of the Holy Cross (Box 7, Folder 51)
      - Rome (Italy), S. Maria Della Scala (Box 7, Folder 52-53)
        52 Altar of St. Teresa
        53 Organ Case, Crucifix and Candlestick
      - Rome (Italy), Seminario Romano -Decorations (Box 7, Folder 54)
      - Rome (Italy), Spada Gallery -Classical Festival (Box 7, Folder 55)
      - Rome (Italy), Veneziani -The Forum Romancum (Box 7, Folder 56)
      - Rome (Italy), Villa Valenti - Gonzaga -Casino (Box 7, Folder 57)
      - Rouen (France), Mus├®e (Box 7, Folder 58-59)
        58 Sarcophagus, Relief, Two Figures
        59 Vase, Pyramid, Two Figures Conversing
      - Sacramento (Calif.), Crocker Art Gallery -Ruined Palace and Equestrian Monument (Box 8, Folder 1)
      - San Diego (Calif.), Jacob M. Heimann - Pyramid, Hermes Statue, Figures (Box 8, Folder 2)
      - San Francisco (Calif.), Palace of the Legion of Honor - Arch of Janus Series (Box 8, Folder 3)
      - Santa Barbara (Calif.), Mrs. Alfred B. Clark -Ruins (Box 8, Folder 4)
      - Santa Barbara (Calif.), Museum of Art -Colonnade Series (Box 8, Folder 5)
      - Sarasota (Florida), Ringling Museum (Box 8, Folder 6-8)
        6 Architecture of a Palace
        7 Circe Entertaining Odysseus
        8 Hermes Appearing to Calypso
      - Sassari (Italy), Museo G.A. Sanna -Studies of Figures (Box 8, Folder 9)
      - Schloss Rondnitz collection -The Raising of Lazarus (Box 8, Folder 10)
      - Seattle (Wash.), Art Museum -Port Scene (Box 8, Folder 11)
      - Serlby Hall (England), Nottinghamshire -Interior of St. Peters (Box 8, Folder 12)
      - Shrublands (England), Victor Saumares (Box 8, Folder 13-16)
        13 Arch and Vase Series
        14 Arch of Constantine and Meta Subens
        15 M. Aurelius Statue in an Exedra
        16 Pile of Ruins
      - Springfield (Mo.), Museum of Fine Arts (Box 8, Folder 17-18)
        17 The Arch of Titus
        18 Ruins and Sibyl Preaching
      - St. Louis (Mo.), City Art Museum -Interior of St. Peters (Box 8, Folder 19)
      - Stockholm (Sweden), Bukowski -Interior of St. Peters (Box 8, Folder 20)
      - Stockholm (Sweden), National Museum (Box 8, Folder 21-22)
        21 Pyramids and Ruins
        22 Ruins
      - Stockholm (Sweden), Nordiska Museet -Wall Decorations (Box 8, Folder 23)
      - Stockholm (Sweden), Jorn Thuring -Pile of Ruins with a Vase (Box 8, Folder 24)
      - Stoneleigh Abbey (England), Lord Leigh -Statues of Senators, Ruins (Box 8, Folder 25)
      - Stourhead (England), National Trust (Box 8, Folder 26-27)
        26 Interior of St. Peters
        27 Marriage at Cana
      - Strangnas (Sweden), Lt. Segel - Copies of the Accademia di S. Luca pair (Box 8, Folder 28)
      - Sutton Place (England), Mr. Paul Getty -Interior of the Parthenon (Box 8, Folder 29)
      - Toledo (Spain), Museum of Art -Ruins (Box 8, Folder 30)
      - Turin (Italy), Palazzo Madama collection -View of the West Facade of the Castle of Rivoli (Box 8, Folder 31)
      - Turin (Italy), Palazzo Reale -View of the East and South Facades of the Castle at Rivoli (Box 8, Folder 32-33)
      - Tyrone (Ireland), Duke of Abercorn (Box 8, Folder 34-35)
        34 Interior of S. Paolo Fuori le Mura
        35 Interior of St. Peters
      - Valence (France), Musée -Statue of Marcus Aurelius in an Exedra (Box 8, Folder 36)
      - Venice (Italy), Accademia -Decorative Doors (Box 8, Folder 37)
      - Venice (Italy), DeMinerbi collection -Festival in S. Apostoli Rome (Box 8, Folder 38)
      - Venice (Calif.), Rezzonico -Interior of St. Peters (Box 8, Folder 39)
      - Versailles (France), Bibliothéque -Piazza S. Pietro (Box 8, Folder 40)
      - Vienna (Austria), Academy (Box 8, Folder 41-42)
        41 Ionic and Corinthian Ruins
        42 Ionic Portico, Lion Statue and Relief
      - Vienna (Austria), private collection -The Via Sacra, Looking Toward the Capitoline (Box 8, Folder 43)
      - Vienna (Austria), Staats-Galerie -Mass of Ruins (Box 8, Folder 44)
      - Warsaw (Poland), Muzeum Narodowe -Ruins with Figure of Belisarius (Box 8, Folder 45)
      - Washington (D.C.), Perry B. Cott -Interior of the Pantheon (Box 8, Folder 46)
      - Washington (D.C.), National Gallery of Art -Interior of the Pantheon (Box 8, Folder 47)
      - Washington (D.C.), Louis Navega -Ruins (Box 8, Folder 48)
      - Washington (D.C.), Mrs. Andrew Parker -Ruins (Box 8, Folder 49)
      - Washington (D.C.), Mrs. Merriweather Post collection -Ruins (Box 8, Folder 50)
      - Weimar (Germany), Staatlichen Kunstsammlungen -Pantheon and Square (Box 8, Folder 51)
      - Williamsburg (Va.), Arcades -Statue of Marcus Aurelius (Box 9, Folder 1)
      - Williamsburg (Va.), Governor's Palace (Box 9, Folder 2-3)
        2 Group of Monuments, Figure Preaching
        3 Ruins With Vase and Circular Temple
      - Williamstown (Mass.), Lawrence Art Museum -Colosseum Series (Box 9, Folder 4)
      - Windsor Castle (England), The Queen (Box 9, Folder 5-7)
        5 Arch of Severus and Other Monuments
        6 Colosseum and Arch of Constantine
        7 Obelisk and Pantheon
      - Wurzburg (Germany), Universtat Kunstmuseum -Landscape with Fisherman (Box 9, Folder 8)
      - Unknown (Box 9, Folder 9-25)
        9 Archway with Tomb of Minerva Medica
        10 Archway, Screen and Statue of Hercules and the Hydra
        11 Figure Addressing a Group, Water in the Foreground
        12 Interior of the Pantheon
        13 Piazza del Popolo
        14 Piazza del Quirinale
        15 Piazza Montecavallo with Horse Tamers Group
        16 Portico of Octavius, Colosseum
        17 Roman Monuments
        18 Ruined Arch, Temple and Vase
        19 Ruins with Vase and Corinthian Structure
        20 Statue of Farnese Hercules, Colosseum, Temple of Fortuna Virilis
        21 Statue of Farnese Hercules, Arch of Titus
        22 Temple of Concord, Vase, Maison Carree
        23 Temple of Saturn, Arch of Constantine, Pyramid
        24 Vase, Pyramid, Temple of Castor and Pollux
        25 Valenti-Gonzaga collection
    - Drawings
      The drawings are arranged alphabetically by city, then specific collection, and then title. This information was gathered at the time of Wunder's research and may not reflect current drawing locations.
      - Amsterdam (Netherlands), de Vries -Garden Scene with Running Figures (Box 10, Folder 1)
      - Amsterdam (Netherlands), de Vries -Pyramid and Ruined Structures (Box 10, Folder 2)
      - Baltimore (Md.), Baltimore Museum of Art -Vase, Exedra and Statue (Box 10, Folder 3)
      - Baltimore (Md.), Douglas H. Gordon -Fantastic Stairway (Box 10, Folder 4)
      - Baltimore (Md.), Peabody Institute (Box 10, Folder 5-7)
        5 Ambulatory of a Hermitage
        6 Mass of Ruined Roman Buildings
        7 Steps of a Palace with Soldiers
      - Bayonne (France), Musée Bonnat -Ruins Overgrown with Vegetation (Box 10, Folder 8)
      - Berlin (Germany), Berlin Museum (Box 10, Folder 9-40)
        9 Architectural Fantasy
        10 Architectural Sketches
        11 Baroque Stage Set
        12 Blind Cupid
        13 Cow Pasture of the Villa Pamphil
        14 Interior of a Church
        15 Interior of the Lateran and a Baroque Altar
        16 Ionic Portico, Circular Temple
        17 Landing of Maria de Medea at Marseilles
        18 Landscape with Cattle and Ruins
        19 Pope Clement XIV Distributing Alms
        20 Ruins of the Palatine
        21 Ruins with Temple of Castor, Pollux and Ruins with Statue of Hercules and Hydra
        22 Single Studies of Figures
        23 Sketchbook
        24 Sketches of Individual Figures
        25 Small Figure Sketches
        26 Standing Monks, Portraits of Men
        27 Studies of Angels and Others
        28 Studies of Cavaliers and a Woman
        29 Studies of Figures
        30 Studies of Figures
        31 Studies of Male and Female Figures
        32 Studies of Male Nudes
        33 Studies of Man's Arm
        34 Studies of Men and a Woman
        35 Studies of Men on Horseback, Others
        36 Studies of Seated Men and Kneeling Women
        37 Studio of Standing Clerics
        38 Studies of Standing and Kneeling Clerics
        39 Studies of Standing Men
        40 View of the Aqueduct of Nero
      - Berlin (Germany), Kaiser Friedrich Museum (Box 10, Folder 41-45)
        41 Standing Figure Resting on Elbow
        42 Studies of Two Male Figures
        43 Study of a Lady Curtsying
        44 Study of Three Male Figures
        45 Two Standing Monks
      - Berlin (Germany), Perl's -Baroque Vaulted Chamber (Box 10, Folder 46)
      - Boston (Mass.), Castano Galleries (Box 10, Folder 47-48)
        47 Studies of 4 Male Figures
        48 Studies of 5 Male Figures
      - Cambridge (Mass.), Fogg Museum of Art (Box 10, Folder 49-50)
        49 Architectural Caprice
        50 Archway with Circular Temple
      - Cambridge (Mass.), Philip Hoter -Ruins with Figures (Box 10, Folder 51)
      - Chicago (Ill.), Art Institute (Box 10, Folder 52-54)
        52 Interior of a Picture Gallery Ancient Rome
        53 Landscape
        54 Standing Figures
      - Darmstadt (Germany), Print Room - View of Piazza di Spagna (Box 10, Folder 55)
      - Dijon (France), Musée (Box 10, Folder 56-57)
        56 Ruins, Statue and Figures
        57 Ruins with Figures Conversing
      - Edinburgh (Scotland), National Gallery of Scotland -Ruined Porticos (Box 10, Folder 58)
      - Florence (Italy), Uffizi (Box 10, Folder 59-82)
        59 Arch of Titus and Ruins
        60 City Square
        61 City Square (theater set)
        62 Classical Landscape
        63 Corinthian Portico and Statue
        64 Hagar and the Angel
        65 Interior of Ruined Roman Baths
        66 Landscape with Groups of Figures
        67 Landscape with Ruins
        68 Landscape with Soldiers, Landscape with Dancers
        69 Portico, Obelisk, Circular Temple
        70 Pyramid, Archway and Ruins
        71 Relief, Vase, Temple of Saturn
        72 Ruined Baroque Structures
        73 Ruined Roman Vaulted Buildings
        74 Ruins with Herdsmen
        75 Ruins and Tomb Monument
        76 Seaport with Baroque Ruins
        77 Seige of a Fort and Classical Landscape
        78 Sphinx and Broken Statue
        79 Steps and Tomb Monument
        80 Temple Interior and Mercury
        81 Temple of Jupiter
        82 Vase, Archway and Pile of Ruins
      - Florence (Italy), A. Gonzalez Palacios -Ruins (Box 11, Folder 1)
      - Frankfurt (Germany), Helbings -The Waterfall at Tivol, 1723 (Box 11, Folder 2)
      - Hagerstown (Md.), William T. Hassett Jr. -Formal Gardens (Box 11, Folder 3)
      - Hamburg (Germany), Kunstnalle -Ruins Composition (Box 11, Folder 4)
      - Lille (France), Musée Wicar Collection (Box 11, Folder 5-7)
        5 Baroque Multi-Domed Structure
        6 Domed Structure with Fountain
        7 Pyramid, Figure Addressing Others
      - London (England), British Museum (Box 11, Folder 8-88)
        8 A Seated Portrait
        9 Architectural Caprice
        10 Boats, Ruins, Group of Figures
        11 Christ in Resurrection
        12 Circular Temple in a Landscape
        13 Garden with Baroque Buildings
        14 Figure Preaching Before a Circular Temple
        15 Landscape with Ruins and Figures
        16 Ruined, Vaulted Arcade
        17 Ruins with Figures on Horseback
        18 Sketchbook -Arms of Clement XIII and Figures
        19 Sketchbook -Bass Fiddler
        20 Sketchbook -Bowing, Kneeling and Standing Men
        21 Sketchbook -Caricature and Man Reading from the Back
        22 Sketchbook -Caricatures
        23 Sketchbook -Ceiling Vault
        24 Sketchbook -Ceiling, Vault and Capitals
        25 Sketchbook -A Cellist
        26 Sketchbook -Child and Kneeling Woman
        27 Sketchbook -Coffered Vault and Statuary
        28 Sketchbook -Column and Statue of a Saint
        29 Sketchbook -Detail of a Skirt and Standing Lady
        30 Sketchbook -Details of a Vatican Building
        31 Sketchbook -Figures of Men
        32 Sketchbook -Figures with Bundles
        33 Sketchbook -Flying Angel
        34 Sketchbook -Guard and Eccliastic[sic] [Ecclesiastic]
        35 Sketchbook -Hand, Seated Man, Eccliastic[sic] [Ecclesiastic]
        36 Sketchbook -Kneeling and Standing Eccliastics[sic] [Ecclesiastics]
        37 Sketchbook -Kneeling and Walking Men
        38 Sketchbook -Kneeling Man with Musket
        39 Sketchbook -Kneeling Men
        40 Sketchbook -Man Leaning on a Staff
        41 Sketchbook -Man Leaning Over a Block